OMKAR PAWAR

DATA ANALYST

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Unit 4 38 Boisdale Street 3127, Melbourne Australia

PHONE

0470373345

EMAIL

omkar.paw26@gmail.com

DATE OF BIRTH

30th August, 1995

LINKS

LinkedIn

<u>Portfolio</u>

GitHub

SKILLS

Tableau, Microsoft Power

Microsoft Excel

SQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Python, R, UWP, UI/UX, Java, Kotlin, C#

Microsoft Excel, Jupyter Notebook, Google Collab

Android, Visual Studios,

Data Analysis and Visualisation

Microsoft Azure Machine Learning

Computer Skills

Leadership Skills

Communication Skills

LANGUAGES

PROFILE

An enthusiastic Data Analyst aiming to work for an organization, providing an opportunity to improve my technical, analytical skills, and knowledge to grow along with the organizational objective. Passionate Computer Engineer with motivated and leadership qualities. Eager to learn new technologies and methodologies. Ability to solve complex problems and transform raw data into structured data. Capability to work as an individual as well as in a team. Hardworking professional with 2 years of experience and a proven knowledge in the field.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Insight Analyst, Victorian School Building Authority

Melbourne

Mar 2023

- Designed, developed, built, implemented and supported BI and Data Warehouse solutions within Victorian School Buildings Authority (VSBA) Reporting platform - SAIL and AIMS data.
- Worked on designing and building of BI solutions that will provide effective reporting and analysis of VSBA data in response to queries from both internal and external stakeholders.
- Built report and data analysis solutions on business requirement for the Victorian School Buildings Authority.
- · Implemented SQL queries for automation on data storage and update.
- · Worked with IBM and Oracle systems for implementing data infrastructure.
- Created SSIS reports using using Business Intelligence Reporting in Visual Studios.
- Used Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio for data storage and query operations.

Data and Analytics - Associate, PwC

Adelaide, Australia

Nov 2022 — Feb 2023

- Working in infrastructure central team to provide data solutions using leading analytical tools.
- · Data consolidation and preparation using Alteryx.
- · Experience using MURAL for team and client engagements.
- Working on housing supply for NSW and creating visual reports using Power BI.

Data Analyst, City of Stonningtion

Melbourne. Australia

Jul 2022 — Oct 2022

- · Working on developing smart city and collecting the data for analysis.
- · Providing database support to the team.
- · Creating data models and producing and implementing data strategies.
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$. Working closely with the stakeholders to provides high end outcome.
- · Collecting Data from IoT sensors and performing data analysis.
- $\cdot\;$ Experience working with JIRA and Confluence.

English

• • • • 0

Hindi

• • • • •

Marathi

• • • • •

- · Coordinating project with the team and performing data operations.
- · Developing dashboards and reports using Power Bl.

Data Analyst, CodeGym

Melbourne, Australia

Nov 2020 — Mar 2021

- Analyzing company's datasets to gain meaningful insights improving process of time taken for student to complete the course and quiz, overall efficiency of every student using Microsoft Azure Machine Learning.
- Work involved data cleaning, data modeling, data analysis, data visualization, SQL and forming data driven solutions.
- · Performed operations on EXCEL for cleaning datasets.
- Created dashboard in Power BI for visualization of prediction made using Random Forest Method on time, course and most enrolled course gaining an efficiency of 90%.
- · Created reports on visualized and analysed data.
- Built a recommendation system for students to enhance ability by providing recommendations on areas to improve.
- Worked in a collaborative environment with 5 other team members and under mentor's supervision
- Ability to work in a fast-paced environment having strong analytical and quantitative problem solving skills.
- Applied languages and platform Microsoft Azure Machine Learning Studio, Microsoft Azure, Python, Power Bl.

Assistant Educator, Camp Australia

Melbourne

Feb 2020 — Jun 2021

- Monitored children in exciting and meaningful activities all the while guiding their growth.
- · Assist coordinator to organize staff rosters for the service.
- · Promote staff environment in training opportunities.
- · Engage with children and kept their safety as a priority.

Software Developer and Analyst, Appristine Technologies

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Dec 2018 — Jul 2019

- Performed hands on experience in UWP, UX Design and Android application development project IJTIMAATI - Meeting.
- Developed skills of working as an individual as well as in a team. Performed APIs and Database connection and SQL query operations.
- Developed problem solving skills while working software development and web development.
- Performed research about developing PDF editor for the requirement of the project.
- · Create data reporting, performed analysis and visualization on data collected.
- · Present the created report with the stakeholders.
- · Started independently on the UWP project and developed from scratch.
- Applied platform and languages Visual Studio, Android Studio, Universal Windows Platform, C#, SQL, PHP, Java.

Software Engineer, Tribbianis Software Solutions

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Jul 2018 — Nov 2018

- · Developed stop words removing and stemming projects using python.
- · Performed functions on datasets for analysis and created a chat bot.
- · Implemented libraries in python and applied in projects.
- · Applied platform and languages Jupyter Notebook, Python.

Software Developer Intern, Tata Consultancy Services

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Aug 2017 — Dec 2017

- Developed a Clinic Management System for Doctors and Patients to view treatment history, book appointment, and keep a track of prescriptions.
- · Tools and languages: Visual Studios, C#, SQL.
- · Learned time management skills under mentor's guidance.

EDUCATION

Master of Data Science, Deakin University

Melbourne, Australia

Nov 2019 — Jul 2021

Major: Data Science.

Languages used: Python, R, SQL.

Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Tableau, Power Bl.

Bachelor of Computer Engineering, University of Pune

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Jul 2014 — Jun 2018

- Major: Computer Engineering.
- Achievements: Final year project in IoT enabled smart switches 2nd Price at PICT project competition.

UNIVERSITY PROJECTS

Developer

Melbourne, Australia

Jul 2020 — Feb 2021

Wellth: A health activity tracker.

- Built a website for health and well-being. User can perform, record activities, and keep a track of health.
- · Languages used HTML, CSS, PHP, SQL.

Developer

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Jul 2017 — May 2018

An Effective Approach for Smart Home Automation using IoT, Pune, Maharashtra, India July 2017 - May 2018

- Developed an IoT smart switch using NodeMCU and IoT platform to control electrical appliances using Mobile Application/ Web Application.
- Tools and languages: Cayenne IoT platform, NodeMCU, Arduino programming language.

CERTIFICATION

SQL (Basic)

Jun 2022 — Jun 2022

HackerRank

SQL (Intermediate)

Jun 2022 — Jun 2022

<u>HackerRank</u>

Learning SAP Analytics Cloud

May 2022 — May 2022

LinkedIn Learning

Testdome certificate for SQL

Nov 2021 — Nov 2022

<u>TestDome certificate for Omkar Chandrashekhar Pawar | TestDome</u>

Python

May 2022 — May 2022

<u>HackerRank</u>

Problem Solving

May 2022 — May 2022

<u>HackerRank</u>

PUBLICATIONS

• BE Project: An Effective Approach for Smart Home Automation using Internet of Things - International Journal of Innovations & Advancement in Computer Science (IJIACS)

REFERENCES

References available upon request